Guide to the Samuel Halperin collection, 1683-2007 MS2236
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Samuel Halperin collection
1486-2007
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Halperin, Samuel
MS2236
13 Linear Feet
This collection contains original and reproductions of lithographs, engravings, and woodcuts of the Holy Land and Europe, cartographic catalogues, and various resources for cartographic collection. The materials date from 1683-2007. The majority of the lithographs were published in the 1830s and 1840s, while the cartographic catalogues are from the 20th Century. The lithographs were produced by noted artists David Roberts, J.M.W. Turner, and others. In the past, Dr. Samuel Halperin has donated art, maps of the Holy Land, and a collection of bibles to George Washington University. Gift of Samuel Halperin, 2007
Restrictions on Access
Some records may be restricted.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Samuel Halperin, 2007 (Accession 2007.074) with an addition in 2009 (Accession 2009.028)
Historical or Biographical Note
Dr. Samuel Halperin (May 10, 1930 - May 6, 2014), was a leader in education policy, has repeatedly donated valuable and significant collections to George Washington University. From 1969-1981, he headed leadership training programs at GW. He was awarded The President's Medal of George Washington University, the highest honor awarded by the President of the University. Past recipients include Vaclav Havel, Victor Borge, Walter Cronkite, Abba Eban, and Mikhail Gorbachev.
Dr. Halperin earned his bachelor's and master's degrees in 1952 and his Ph.D. in 1956, all in political science and all at Washington University in St. Louis. He began teaching political science at Wayne State University before winning a Congressional Fellowship from the American Political Science Association. He was in Washington D.C. during President Lyndon Johnson's Great Society and became an avid participant. As assistant U.S. commissioner of education for legislation, and, later, as a deputy assistant secretary of health, education, and welfare, he helped craft the historic church-state compromise that cleared the way for passage of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965, providing federal funding for programs to help low-income children in public and private schools. He was also active in the Higher Education Act, which provided substantial new sources of financial aid for college students.
In 1986, Dr. Halperin went to the William T. Grant Foundation as the study director of its Commission on Work, Family, and Citizenship. There, he co-authored two landmark reports, "The Forgotten Half: Non-College Youth in America" and "The Forgotten Half: Pathways to Success for America's Youth and Young Families." In an attempt to enact recommendations from these reports, Dr. Halperin founded the American Youth Policy Forum (AYPF) in 1993. The AYPF brings together various interested parties with the goal of bridging the gap between research, policy, and practice in the fields of education, youth development, and employment readiness.
Dr. Halperin also served as President of the Institute for Educational Leadership, and has written or edited a dozen books on the political process and educational policy. He has taught at American, Duke, and Columbia Universities. In addition to his GW honor and numerous other distinctions, he has received the American Association of Community College's Harry S. Truman Award.
Collection Scope and Content
This collection contains original and reproductions of lithographs, engravings and woodcuts of the Holy Land and Europe, cartographic catalogues, and various resources for cartographic collection. The materials date from 1486-2007. The majority of the lithographs were published in the 1830s and 1840s, while the cartographic catalogues are from the 20th Century. The lithographs were produced by noted artists David Roberts, J.M.W. Turner, and others.
In the past, Dr. Samuel Halperin has donated art, maps of the Holy Land, and a collection of bibles to George Washington University.
Collection Organization
Organized into four series: David Roberts lithographs, Lithographs from the Holy Land and Europe, Cartographic catalogues, and Cartographic collection resources.
Description and travel; Palestine; Israel; Jerusalem; Catalogs; Cartography; Guidebooks; Lithographs; Middle East; Europe; Russia; Odessa (Ukraine); Historical maps; Tourist maps; Istanbul (Turkey); Maps; Turner, J. M. W. (Joseph Mallord William); Roberts, David, 1796-1864 (Holy Land); Richard B. Arkway Inc.; Potter, Jonathan; Halperin, Samuel; Francis Edwards (Firm); Bartlett, W. H. (William Henry)
- David Roberts lithographs, MS2236 Series 1; 1 Linear feet
  Scope and Contents note
  This series contains lithographs produced by David Roberts. Most of the lithographs are hand-colored although a few are the uncolored originals. They are lithographs from various locations in the Holy Land, and are arranged chronologically. Roberts (1796-1864), was a Scottish painter born in Edinburgh, and is known primarily for his detailed prints of Egypt and the Near East produced during the 1840s from sketches made during long tours of the region. This work, and his large oil paintings of similar subjects, made him a prominent Orientalist painter. In 1838, Roberts toured Egypt, Nubia, the Sinai, the Holy Land, Jordan and Lebanon. Throughout, he produced a vast collection of drawings and watercourse sketches. He returned to Edinburgh in 1840 and worked with lithographer Louis Haghe to produce the lavishly illustrated plates of the Sketches in the Holy Land and Syria, and Egypt and Nubia series. Roberts died suddenly in 1864, though after more than 150 years his paintings are still the most beloved and popular illustrations of Egypt and are highly sought after by collectors.
  - The Pool of Bethesda, 1839 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - The Convent of St. Catherine, Mount Sinai, 1839 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - The Convent of St. Catherine with Mount Horeb, 1839 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Jerusalem from the Mount of Olives, 1841 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Citadel of Jerusalem, 1841 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Askelon, 1842 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Convent of St. Catherine, Mount Sinai (with Greek Orthodox Priests, 1840 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Caiphas (Haifa), Looking towards Mount Carmel, 1843 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Approach to Mount Sinai, 1845 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Jerusalem from the South, 1841 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Jerusalem from the North, 1841 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - El Deir, Petra, 1842 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Island of Graia, Gulf of Akabah (Coral Island near Eilat & Jordan's Akabah), 1844 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Jericho, 1842 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    General note
    Uncolored original
  - Gaza, 1843 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Town of Tiberias, Looking towards Lebanon with Mount Hernon, 1844 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Exterior of the Holy Sepulchre, 1841 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Damascus Gate, 1841 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Fortress of Akabah (Jordan), 1844 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Jaffa, 1845 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - St. Jean D'Acre, 1843 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Conference of Arabs, 1842 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Encampment of the Pilgrims at Jericho, 1839 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Ashdod, 1843 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Le Puits De Bethesda (Pool of Bethesda), 1851 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Petra, 1834 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    Donated separately and moved into this collection.
  - Jerusalem - The Mosque of Omar, 1835 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Jerusalem, circa 1840 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - La Mosquee D'Omar situee sur l'emplacement du temple (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Jerusalem from the Mount of Olives (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - St. Jean D'acre (Box 24, Folder 3)
- Lithographs, engravings and woodcuts from the Holy Land and Europe, 1486-1880; MS2236 Series 2; 3 Linear feet
  This series is composed primarily of lithographs, woodcuts and engravings of the Holy Land, though there are a few from various European cities. They range in date from 1683-1880, while the bulk was published in the 1830s and 1840s. A handful of the drawings were done by well-known artist J.M.W. Turner, who was a colleague of David Roberts, and published in London. The collection is divided into two sections, one focusing on the Holy Land, the other on Europe. Both sections are organized chronologically, with undated lithographs in the back of each section. Most of the lithographs are matted.
  Arrangement
  Arranged in no particular order.
  - Map of Holy Land, 1714 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Jerusalem From the Mount of Olives, circa 1840 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Jerusalem [1/2], circa 1840 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Jerusalem [2/2], circa 1840 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Baths and the City of Tiberias, 1845 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Pool of Hezekiah, Jerusalem, circa 1860 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Tiberias, 1881 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Ruinen von Selah (Petra) (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Picturesque Palestine, Sinai and Egypt (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - The Bosphorus, Constantinople (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Jerusalem and the Mount of Olives, circa 1830 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Jerusalem, circa 1830 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Jersalem From the Mount of Olives [1/2], 1835 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Jersalem From the Mount of Olives [2/2], 1835 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Mount Zion, Jerusalem (Mosque of David), 1836 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Petra, circa 1840 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Jerusalem From the Mount of Olives, circa 1840 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    Lithograph by H. Warren
  - Jerusalem From the Mount of Olives, circa 1840 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    Lithograph by Gray and Son (publisher)
  - Jerusalem, 1841 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    Lithograph by W.H. Bartlett
  - Jerusalem From the Mount of Olives, circa 1850 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    Lithograph by William Wright (publisher)
  - Mount Zion, Jerusalem, 1857 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Mount Zion, 1867 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    Lithograph by W. Miller
  - Moscow, 1683 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Der Dogenpallast in Venedig (Venice), 1830 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Oxford, From the Meadows, 1830 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Die Moscaiviten (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Der Moscoivitifche Czaar (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Maps and drawings of Moscow, Europe (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Odessa (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Petersburg - Inneres der Nikolskoi-Kirche (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Die Alexandersaule in St. Petersburg (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Die Kasan-Kirche in St. Petersburg (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Gibraltar (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Jerusalem by Sebastian Munster, from his book "Cosmographia," French Edition, Woodcut, 1550; Series 2 (Flat box 25, Item 1)
    Scope and Contents
    This a reproduction
  - Jerusalem, by Breydenbach, Bernard ( -1497), from his book "Sanctarum preregrinatorum", woodcut, Mainz, 1486; Series 2 (Flat box 25, Item 2)
  - Jerusalem, by Seutter, Matthaeus (1678-1757), a plan and a view of The Holy City, Copper engraving Augsburg, 1728; Series 2 (Flat box 25, Item 3)
  - Jerusalem, Description of the City's sites, from a French book, Copper engraving, 17th century; Series 2 (Flat box 25, Item 4)
  - Jerusalem, The destruction of the City, by H. Schedei, from "Liber Chronicarum", Woodcut, Nurenberg, 1493; Series 2 (Flat box 25, Item 5)
  - Jerusalem, The Old City, by John G. Back, from a German Bible, 18th century; Series 2 (Flat box 25, Item 6)
  - Jerusalem, The Holy City, by F. Hogenberg-G. Braun, Copper engraving, Cologne, 1575; Series 2 (Flat box 25, Item 7)
  - Bar-Yaakov, Avraham (1650- ) The Holy Land, The first Hebrew Map, published in the Amsterdam Haggadah, 1696; Series 2 (Flat box 25, Item 8)
    This a reproduction. Courtesy of The National Maritime Museum. Haifa
  - Tilleman, Stella-Stolz (1525-1589), Map of The Holy Land, dived into tribes, Copper engraving, 1586; Series 2 (Flat box 25, Item 9)
  - H. Jaillot-N. Sanson, Map of The Holy Land with the Tribes of Israel, Paris, 1696; Series 2 (Flat box 25, Item 10)
  - Christian Adrichom (1553-1585), Map of the Holy Land and the Tribes of Israel, from the book "Theatrum Terrae Sanctae", Cologne, 1590; Series 2 (Flat box 25, Item 11)
    This a reproduction.
  - John Speed (1552-1629), Map of the Holy Land, Egypt and a plan of Jerusalem, London, 1651; Series 2 (Flat box 25, Item 12)
  - The Tower of Babylon, from a 15th century french manuscript, Series 2 (Flat box 25, Item 13)
  - Jerusalem from a 15th century manuscript, Series 2 (Flat box 25, Item 14)
  - M. von Lochom, Map of the Holy Land with additional maps of Jerusalem, Exodus from Egypt, Great Syria, Paris, 1641; Series 2 (Flat box 25, Item 15)
    This a reproduction. Courtesy of the National Maritime Museum, Haifa
  - De-Schaas, Lucas-Brandis (15th cent.), Map of The Holy Land, from the Incunabula "Rudimentum novitiorum", Woodcut Lubeck, 1475; Series 2 (Flat box 25, Item 16)
  - T. Fuller: Map of Terra Moriah-Jerusalem, from this book "A pisgah-site of Palestine," London, 1650; Series 2 (Flat box 25, Item 17)
  - Mount of Olives and Valley of Jehoshaphat, undated; Series 2 (Flat box 25, Item 18)
    Text on document "[From the Drawing by H. A. Harper] The plateau in the foreground is believed to be the Site of the Crucificxion.
  - Joppa, From the Exhibition of Mr. H.A. Harper's Views of the Holy Land., 1872; Series 2 (Flat box 25, Item 19)
  - Vue de Jerusalem (View of Jerusalem), circa 1870; Series 2 (Box 26, Item 1)
  - Travel Notes in Bible Lands, undated; Series 2 (Box 26, Item 2)
  - An Artist's Pilgrimage to the Holy Land, 1878; Series 2 (Box 26, Item 3)
  - The Church of the Redeemer from Harper's Weekly, 8 October 1898; Series 2 (Box 26, Item 4)
  - The Bab Zuweyleh, or Gate of the Kutb, 1880; Series 2 (Box 26, Item 5)
  - Modern Jerusalem, 1845; Series 2 (Box 26, Item 6)
  - Secretary Hay's Note and the Jewish Question, 1802; Series 2 (Box 26, Item 7)
  - Israel/The United States of America, Arthur Szyk, 1945, 1949; Series 2 (Box 26, Item 8)
  - Arthur Zryk -- Hillel, undated; Series 2 (Box 26, Item 9)
  - Israel Provisional Government Official Gazette, 14 May 1948; Series 2 (Box 26, Item 10)
  - The Chosen People, 1880 (Box 26, Item 11)
  - Hartmann Schedel, The Nuremburg Chronicle, 1493; Series 2 (Box 26, Item 11)
  - Hartmann Schedel, The Nuremburg Chronicle, 1493 (Box 26, Item 12)
  - Die Juden zu Worms todten fich untereinam der im Angesicht der fie verfolgenden Kreutzfahrer, 1880; Series 2 (Box 26, Item 13)
  - The Colonization of Yeshiva-Students in Eretz-Israel Company, circa 1930; Series 2 (Box 26, Item 14)
  - Scenes in the Holy Land, 1870; Series 2 (Box 27, Item 1)
  - Ceremonies of the Jews upon the Sabbath Day. Copperplate engraving from Calmet's Bible., 1732; Series 2 (Box 27, Item 2)
  - Redemption of the First Born. Copperplate engraving from Calmet's Bible., 1732; Series 2 (Box 27, Item 3)
  - The Ceremonies of a Jewish Wedding. Copperplate engraving from Calmet's Bible., 1732; Series 2 (Box 27, Item 4)
  - The Jewish Passover. Copperplate engraving from Calmet's Bible., 1732; Series 2 (Box 27, Item 5)
  - The Golden Candle-stick with Seven Branches. Copperplate engraving from Calmet's Bible., 1732; Series 2 (Box 27, Item 6)
  - An Artist's Pilgrimage to the Holy Land. From The Graphic., 3 August 1878; Series 2 (Box 27, Item 7)
  - The City of Jerusalem, 1858; Series 2 (Box 27, Item 8)
  - Birds-Eye View of the Holy Land, circa 1880; Series 2 (Box 27, Item 9)
  - Ill-Treatment of the Jews in Russia. From the Illustrated London News., 4 June 1884; Series 2 (Box 28, Item 1)
  - Felt Flags, circa 1880; Series 2 (Box 28, Item 2)
    10 felt flags from various locations, including Belgium and Germany.
  - Reproduction of artwork, circa 1946; Series 2 (Box 28, Item 3)
  - The Holy Sepulchre. Convent of the Holy Land, At Nazareth, 1880; Series 2 (Box 28, Item 4)
  - 46- and 48-star United States Flags., Undated; Series 2 (Box 28, Item 5)
  - Jerusalem in Her Fall, circa 1870; Series 2 (Box 28, Item 6)
  - The Explorations at Jerusalem. From the Illustrated London News., 24 April 1869; Series 2 (Box 28, Item 7)
  - The English Bible before King James., 1964; Series 2 (Box 28, Item 8)
  - Thirty & Eight Gates to the Bible. Shmuel Bonneh., Undated; Series 2 (Box 28, Item 9)
  - Eastern US Cities and their environs., circa 1831; Series 2 (Box 28, Item 10)
  - Jerusalem / Mosilee, Undated; Series 2 (Box 28, Item 11)
  - Akedat Yitshak, undated; Series 2 (Box 28, Item 12)
    General
    Biblical scene relating the binding of Isaac, surrounded by the verses in Genesis 22, read shortly after the Jewish New Year. The placard may be intended as a wall hanging for a sukkah.
  - Mizrah, circa 1900; Series 2 (Box 28, Item 13)
    Also known as "Sheviti", placard with color illustrated biblical verses placed on the eastern wall of the prayer room above the prayer leader's lectern.
  - Single leaf from from the Hagadat Volakh (The Wolloch Haggadah), Pessach Haggadah in Memory of the Holocaust, 1985; Series 2 (Box 28, Item 14)
    Illustrations by David Wander, calligraphy and micrography by Yonah Weinreb. This leaf contains the text of the passage beginning Ve-hi she-amdah. The illustration below shows pyramids in the background and what appear to be modern industrial crematoria in the foreground.
  - Printed acknowledgement form for donations to the Yeshivah (College) Torat Hayim ( Torath Haim) in Jerusalem, Palestine., undated; Series 2 (Box 28, Item 15)
    Jerusalem: A.L. Monzon lithographic press, n.d. (late 19th-early 20th century). Hebrew and German seal of the College on bottom left. The names of the College's administrators, Rabbi Sorach Epstein and Rabbi Simcha Winograd, are given in an English address at the bottom.
  - Illustrations by David Wander, calligraphy and micrography by Yonah Weinreb. This leaf contains the concluding paragraph of the Haggadah text, with the words Le-shanah ha-ba'ah bi Yrushalayim in large colored letters below., undated; Series 2 (Box 28, Item 16)
  - Interior of the Mosque of the Sultan El Ghoree, 1849; Series 2 (Box 30, Item 1)
    Immediate Source of Acquisition
    Gift of Samuel Halperin, November 1995.
  - Pompey's Pillar, Alexandria, 1846; Series 2 (Box 30, Item 2)
  - Mosque of Sultan Hassan fron the Great Square of the Rameyleh, 1840; Series 2 (Box 30, Item 3)
  - Modern Mansion showing the Arabesque Architecture of Cairo, 1849; Series 2 (Box 30, Item 4)
  - Bazaar of the Coppersmiths, Cairo, 1848; Series 2 (Box 30, Item 5)
  - The Coffee Shop, 1849; Series 2 (Box 30, Item 6)
  - Bullack, Cairo, 1849; Series 2 (Box 30, Item 7)
  - View on the Nile looking towards the Pyramids of Dashour and Saccara, 1846; Series 2 (Box 30, Item 8)
- Cartographic catalogues, MS2236 Series 3; 7.5 Linear feet
  The material of this series is a collection of cartographic catalogues from around the world. Most of the catalogues are undated, including some from 2007. These catalogues list the collection of maps offered by various dealers. The largest collection of catalogues comes from Francis Edwards, Jonathan Potter, and Richard Arkway, Inc. There are a few catalogues in foreign languages, notably German and Italian. This series is arranged alphabetically in document boxes, with map dealers arranged by their first names (i.e., Jonathan Potter Gallery is listed under "J" rather than "P").
  - Ad Orientem, Ltd., 1977 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Adab Books, Nos. 30, 34-35 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Antiquariaat Frits Knuf Buren (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Antiquariat Holgev Christoph & Co. (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Archaeologia, 1986-1989 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Archaeologia, 1990-1991 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Barry Lawrence Ruderman Old Historic Maps and Prints (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Bauman Rare Books (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Bernard Quaritch, Ltd. (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Bernard Shapero Rare Books (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Bernard Shapero Rare Books (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Bernard Shapero Rare Books (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Bloomsbury Auctions, 01/27/2005-10/13/2005 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Bloomsbury Auctions, 10/20/2005 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Bloomsbury Auctions, 01/19/2006 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Bloomsbury Auctions, 06/01/2006 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Bloomsbury Auctions, 06/15/2006 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Bloomsbury Auctions, 12/14/2006 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Bloomsbury Auctions, 11/01/2007-11/02/2007 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Buddenbrooks - To the ends of the Earth, Vol. 2 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - C. Broekema, no 59-67 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Cartographic Arts (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Cartes Geographiques Anciennes, 1994-2000 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Cartes Geographiques Anciennes, 2001-2004 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Cartes Geographiques Anciennes, 2005-2006 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Christie's (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Clive Farahar (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - D&E Lake ,Ltd. - no. 12 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Damms Antikvariat (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - David Low (Booksellers), Ltd. (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Dawson's Bookshop (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Finden (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Francis Edwards, no. 1078, 1079, 1085 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Francis Edwards, no. 1086, 1088, 1089, 1093 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Francis Edwards, no. 1100, 1107, 1113, 1118, 1123, 1127 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Francis Edwards, no. 1135, 1137, 1139 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Francis Edwards, no. 1140, 1141, 1143, 1144 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Francis Edwards, no. 1145, 1146, 1152, 1153 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Francis Edwards, no. 1155-1158 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Francis Edwards, no. 1164-1168 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Francis Edwards, no. 1169-1171, 1178, 1180-1181 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Francis Edwards, no. 1183-1184, 1186-1188 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Francis Edwards, no. 1193-1196, 1198, 1214 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Francis Edwards, in Cambridge, no. 1 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Francis Edwards, in London, no. 1-3, 5 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Francis Edwards, in London, no. 6-7 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - H.P. Kraus, no. 132, 143 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Hauswedell & Nolte, 11/2007 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Henry Sotheran, Ltd. (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Hunersdorff, no. 9 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Interlibrum Vaduz (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - J. & S.L. Bonham (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - J.L. Beijers BV (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - J.T. Books (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Jeff Weber Rare Books (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - JoAnn & Richard Casten, no. 1-75, 1-77, 1-87, 1-90, 1-91, III, IV (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - John Trotter (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Johnson's List of Geographic and Educational Works, comprising atlases, maps, etc., 1857 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Jonathan Potter, Ltd. - no. 3-7, 10-12 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    Choice Items from stock
  - Jonathan Potter, Ltd. - no. 13-15 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Jonathan Potter, Ltd. - no. 16-18 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Jonathan Potter, Ltd., Fine, Decorative and Rare Old Maps (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Jonathan Potter, Ltd., A Selection of Antique Maps, 1981-1983 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Jonathan Potter, Ltd., A Selection of Antique Maps, 1984 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Jonathan Potter, Ltd., A Selection of Antique Maps, 1992 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Jonathan Potter, Ltd., A Selection of Antique Maps, 2001-2003 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Jonathan Potter, Ltd., A Selection of Antique Maps, 2004-2006 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - L.S. Straight (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Library of Congress (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Libreria L. Gonnelli & Figli, S.A.S. (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Libreria Oreste Gozzini (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Lombard Antiquarian Maps and Prints (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Maggs Brothers, no. 413 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Maggs Brothers, no. 519 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Maggs Brothers, no. 693, 710, 761 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Maggs Brothers, no. 972 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Map House of London (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Mappamundi, Ltd. (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Mapquest, No. 6 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Martayan Lan, no. 4, 6-7, 10, 12 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Martayan Lan, no. 13, 17, 20-21, 23 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Martayan Lan, no. 24, 26-27, 29 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Martayan Lan, no. 30-31, 33 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Martayan Lan, no. 34-35 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Martayan Lan, New Series, no. 1, 3 (Box 11, Folder 4)